{"Topic": "Freedom Struggle - Places", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "The violent incident at Chauri Chaura in Uttar Pradesh occurred during which of the following movements?", "op1": "Civil disobedience", "op2": "Non-cooperation", "op3": "Quit India", "op4": "Poorna Swaraj", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Satyagraha at which of the following places earned Vallabhbhai Patel the title of Sardar", "op1": "Kheda", "op2": "Ahmedabad", "op3": "Bardoli", "op4": "Dandi", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "At which of the following places did Mahatma Gandhi launch a Satyagraha to help the oppressed indigo farmers?", "op1": "Kheda", "op2": "Bardoli", "op3": "Champaran", "op4": "Dandi", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Satyagraha at which of the following places was NOT related to the problems of farmers?", "op1": "Ahmedabad", "op2": "Kheda", "op3": "Bardoli", "op4": "Champaran", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following figured in the TIME magazine\u2019s Top 10 Most Influential Protests of all time recently?", "op1": "Quit India Movement", "op2": "Champaran Satyagraha", "op3": "Bardoli Satyagraha", "op4": "Salt Satyagraha", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following was sent to the dreaded Cellular Jail in Port Blair for his involvement in Kakori train robbery", "op1": "Ramprasad Bismil", "op2": "Sachindranath Sanyal", "op3": "Vinayak Savarkar", "op4": "Rash Behari Bose", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following was not a fall out of the Jallianwala Bagh incident?", "op1": "A only", "op2": "B only", "op3": "A and B", "op4": "B and C", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "At which of the following places was the Flag Satyagraha successfully led by Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel?", "op1": "Poona", "op2": "Nagpur", "op3": "Bardoli", "op4": "Bombay", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Moirang, the place at which Indian National Army hoisted the national Flag during world War II is located in", "op1": "Tripura", "op2": "Andaman islands", "op3": "Bangladesh", "op4": "Manipur", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Stuttgart, the place at which Madame Bhikaji Cama unfurled the Indian Flag is located in", "op1": "France", "op2": "Japan", "op3": "Germany", "op4": "U S A", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following carried out the Salt Satyagraha at Vedaranyam in Tamilnadu?", "op1": "Dr. Radhakrishnan", "op2": "C Rajagopalachari", "op3": "P Sitarammaiah", "op4": "Maulana Azad", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of these incidents is not associated with lahore", "op1": "Launch of Quit India movement", "op2": "Fasting of Jatin Das", "op3": "Execution of Bhagat Singh", "op4": "Poorna Swaraj resolution", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Gowalia Tank Maidan, at which Aruna Asaf Ali hoisted the Indian Tricolour is located in", "op1": "Port Blair", "op2": "Bombay", "op3": "Lahore", "op4": "Chittagong", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Match the following", "op1": "A-4; B-2; C-3; D-1", "op2": "A-4; B-3; C-2; D-1", "op3": "A-1; B-3; C-2; D-4", "op4": "A-1; B-3; C-2; D-4", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Arrange the following in the correct chronological order as they occurred during the freedom struggle.", "op1": "A \u2013 B \u2013 C - D", "op2": "A \u2013 D \u2013 C - B", "op3": "D \u2013 A \u2013 C - B", "op4": "C \u2013 D \u2013 B - A", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Champaran Satyagraha   B. Dandi March C. Nagpur Flag Satyagraha D. Kheda Satyagraha", "op1": "1 - c; 2 - b; 3 - c", "op2": "1 - b; 2 - a; 3 - c", "op3": "1 - a; 2 - c; 3 - b", "op4": "1 - b; 2 - c; 3 - a", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Match the following", "op1": "Nagpur", "op2": "Lahore", "op3": "Pune", "op4": "Hyderabad", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Aga Khan Palace, where Mahatma Gandhi was imprisoned and where Kasturba Gandhi breathed her last is located in", "op1": "Sabarmati", "op2": "Sewagram", "op3": "Wardha", "op4": "Surat", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "From which place did Mahatma Gandhi commence his historic march to Dandi?", "op1": "1 \u2013 c; 2 - a; 3 - b", "op2": "1 \u2013 b; 2 - c; 3 - a", "op3": "1 \u2013 a; 2 \u2013 b; 3 - c", "op4": "1 \u2013 c; 2 - b; 3 - a", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Match the following", "op1": "Gorakhpur", "op2": "Allahabad", "op3": "Moradabad", "op4": "Lucknow", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which district is Kakori, the place famous for train dacoity by Indian revolutionaries located?", "op1": "Lahore", "op2": "Calcutta", "op3": "Bombay", "op4": "Lucknow"}]}